# Sean Haines

971-404-4048 seanhaines13@gmail.com

Github • LinkedIn • Portfolio

## Overview

I consider myself a fully stacked Front-End developer with a deep passion for design, user experience and interface. I have the ability to develop web applications from concept to implementation with experienced in user research, testing and development. My professional goals are to continuously add new tools of the trade to my utility belt while working with an amazing and driven team.

## Education

Full Stack Web Development, 2015

Coding Dojo, Bellevue, Washington

Bachelor of Arts in Community Health Education, 2008

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

# **Professional Experience**

**UI Developer,** Aug. 2015 – *Present* Avanade, Seattle, Washington

I was brought on a short-term contract to assist in the ExxonMobil Fuel & Lubes Division to implement and develop new front-end tools and resources utilizing SCSS, Angular and jQuery.

**Web Developer,** May 2015 – *Present* Freelance Web Designer & Developer

**Team Lead,** Mar. 2013 – Feb. 2015

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

Led team meetings to discuss daily tasks and monthly goals to ensure high levels of efficiency and customer service within the organization. Assisted with the screening, hiring and training of new staff while managing the day-to-day operations of the case management team. Coordinated new strategies and process improvements. Compiled monthly, quarterly and annual reports showing the success and growth of all programs. Developed training materials.

Case Manager II, May 2010 – Feb. 2013

Project Access Northwest, Seattle, Washington

Restructured dental program's processes, which increased client referral numbers by 1,200% over 2 years. Scheduled high volumes of medical and dental appointments across multiple counties for uninsured and Medicaid clients. Daily data entry of incoming referrals, medical chart notes, enrollment applications, and clinical records requests.

Eligibility and Enrollment Specialist, Jun. 2008 – Apr. 2010

Coalition of Community Health Clinics, Portland, Oregon

Processed all applications, enrollments and denials. I was responsible for the coordination of patient to provider assignments, patient orientations, surveys, appointments, and interpretive services.

# **Technical Toolbox**

#### Languages

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, SASS/SCSS, JADE

#### Libraries & Frameworks

Angular.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, CodeIgniter, Express.js, Socket.io, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose.js

#### **Databases**

Mongodb, MySQL

#### Servers

Apache, Node.js

#### **Tools**

Gulp.js, Sublime Text, Atom Text Editor, Visual Studio, Git/Github, Terminal/Command Line

### Methodology

MVC, OOP, RESTful

